Studer, Norman; Papers apap116
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Films, ca. 1946-1962; Undated; 7; 9 films
  - Untitled Woodland Film, 1960; 11 minutes Color; genreform: 8mm (Film 5)
    This film includes some title cards, which are indicated here in quotation marks. Camp Woodland activities including: "Camp Woodland 1960," "Sunday Meeting," dancing, eating dinner, "Pete Seeger" performing onstage, "1960 Folk Festival," dancing, choral performance, "Good-Bye to Campers," "Rusty Bringing Up Supplies," boy pulling a sled of supplies through the snow, playing in the snow, and downhill skiing.
  - Untitled Woodland Film, 1961; 25 minutes Color; genreform: 8mm (Film 6)
    This film includes some title cards, which are indicated here in quotation marks. Camp Woodland activities including: "1961 Olympics at Camp Woodland," races in the swimming pool, "Work Camp Contest" (1:47), "Middle Camp High Jump" (2:45), "At the Pool" (3:35), Native American dancers providing a demonstration for campers (12:03), "Ballgame," "Visiting Day," "Senior Camp," "Mardi Gras," campers in raingear, and campers leaving camp for the summer.
  - Untitled Woodland Film, Undated; 9 minutes, 15 seconds Black and White; genreform: 16mm (Film 7)
    Camp Woodland activities including: campers, farm animals, arts and crafts, sports, dancing (Sara Abelson?), campers carrying food baskets, campers eating, Norman Studer with campers at a lake, campers drinking milk, foot races, jungle gym, swimming in camp pool, and dancing.
  - Untitled Woodland Film, Undated; 11 minutes, 45 seconds Color; genreform: 16mm (Film 8)
    A group of Camp Woodland campers and counselors on a canoe trip. Includes sequences of campers swimming in a lake, paddling canoes, carrying canoes down roads, and their campsite.
  - Untitled Film, Undated (Film 9)
    No description is available.
- Writings, 1926-1997; Undated; 8; 3.85 cubic ft.
  Subseries 1 is arranged alphabetically and Subseries 2 is chronological.
  This series contains all Norman Studer's writings from diaries to published articles, including posthumous reprints. There also are works co-written with others or background materials authored by other individuals, such as Camp Woodland campers. The series is sub-divided into Studer's writing and his diaries and travelogues.
  - Writings of, 1926-1997; Undated; 8.1
    This subseries contains manuscript and typescript drafts, typescripts, notes, reprints, monographs, and a small amount of correspondence related to Studer's writing projects. Of interest are two typescript drafts of unpublished projects: Community Life and Woodland Story both of which are reflective pieces examining Studer's life and work at the Downtown Community School and Camp Woodland respectively. Please note that Studer published some Woodland Story chapters separately. For instance, "Folklore from a Valley that Died" (Chapter 9) was a standalone article in New York Folklore Quarterly in 1956. The standalone article "Yarns of a Catskill Woodsman" (Chapter 16) appeared in New York Folklore Quarterly in 1955. "Mike Todd's Story" (Chapter 11) later evolved into and was published as A Catskill Woodsman. A draft of Woodland Story's Chapter 17 entitled "Our Catskill Teachers" also appears as a section of a draft of Chapter 3. Therefore draft text is found in both files. This collection is missing later draft chapters of Woodland Story so there are gaps in the order.
    Many of the unpublished writings in this series reflect Studer's interest in the folk culture of the Catskills, such as "Action on Dingle Hill," "Forgotten Hero of New York's Slave Railway," "Local Song Writing in the Catskills," and "A Quest for American Roots." Also of interest is an early draft of Folk Songs of the Catskills entitled Music of the Catskills and a final typescript draft of Folk Songs of the Catskills, a collaborative projected compiled and edited by Norman Cazden, Herbert Haufrecht, and Norman Studer.
    - "Action in the American Tradition", Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 1)
    - "Action on Dingle Hill," Anti-Rent Wars Research, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 2)
    - "Action on Dingle Hill," Typescript, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 3)
    - "Action on Dingle Hill," Typescript Draft with Annotations, 1958; Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 4)
    - "All the Homespun Days", 1961 (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 5)
    - American History, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 6)
    - Articles to be Revised, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 7)
    - "Bark Shanty", Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 8)
    - Bibliography of Writings on Education, 1970 (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 9)
    - "Big Mose, New York's Own Paul Bunyan", 1943; 1951; Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 10)
    - "Boney Quillen of the Catskills", 1949; 1951; Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 11)
    - "Camp Woodland Trips", Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 12)
    - "The Cannonsville Story", 1957 (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 13)
    - "Captain Jack: War of the Lava Beds", 1963; Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 14)
    - Castle Clinton, 1951; Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 15)
    - Catskill Trip, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 16)
    - A Catskill Woodsman: Mike Todd's Story, 1988 (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 17)
    - A Catskill Woodsman: Mike Todd's Story, Clippings and Reviews, 1981; 1988 (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 18)
    - A Catskill Woodsman: Mike Todd's Story, Interviews, 1964; Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 19)
    - A Catskill Woodsman: Mike Todd's Story, Permission to Use Published Materials, 1978; Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 20)
    - A Catskill Woodsman: Mike Todd's Story, Third Printing Celebration, 1997 (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 21)
    - A Catskill Woodsman: Mike Todd's Story, Typed Draft, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 22)
    - "The Child's Roots in the City", Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 23)
    - "The Child Went Forth", Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 24)
    - "Children Without Race Prejudice", Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 25)
    - "City Slickers in the Catskill Woods", Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 26)
    - Community Life, Notes, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 27)
    - Community Life, Chapter 1 - Progressive Education: Beginnings, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 28)
    - Community Life, Chapter 2 - A Viable Community, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 29)
    - Community Life, Chapter 2 - Lost Community, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 30)
    - Community Life, Chapter 3 - The Larkin Committee, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 31)
    - Community Life, Chapter 4 - Intergroup Education: Our Greatest Public Service, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 32)
    - Community Life, Chapter 5 - Revolt the 60s, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 33)
    - Community Life, Chapter 6 - Planning for Intercultural Growth, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 34)
    - Community Life, Chapter 7 - Cooperative Into Corporation, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 35)
    - Community Life, Chapter 8 - Talking to Some Future Generations, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 36)
    - Edwin Arlington Robinson, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 37)
    - Elisabeth Irwin High School, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 38)
    - Eric and Michael, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 39)
    - "Experience and Expression", Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 40)
    - "Faulkner- Descriptions, His Philosophy", Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 41)
    - "Figures on the Rocks," Poem About Zadoc Pratt, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 42)
    - Film and Writing Ideas, 1962; 1970; Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 43)
    - "Folk Festival of the Catskills", 1955; Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 44)
    - "Folk Museum of the Catskills", Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 45)
    - Folk Songs of the Catskills, Chapter 1 - Lumbering, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 46)
    - Folk Songs of the Catskills, Chapter 2 - Songs of War and Battle, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 47)
    - Folk Songs of the Catskills, Chapter 3 - Ballads About True Love, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 48)
    - Folk Songs of the Catskills, Chapter 4 - Courting Too Slow, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 49)
    - Folk Songs of the Catskills, Chapter 5 - Love Meets Obstacles, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 50)
    - Folk Songs of the Catskills, Chapter 6 - Tragedies, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 51)
    - Folk Songs of the Catskills, Chapter 7 - Legends, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 52)
    - Folk Songs of the Catskills, Chapter 8 - Religious Songs, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 53)
    - Folk Songs of the Catskills, Chapter 9 - Pioneer Days, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 54)
    - Folk Songs of the Catskills, Chapter 10 - Working and Hard Times, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 55)
    - Folk Songs of the Catskills, Chapter 11 - Shabby-Genteel, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 56)
    - Folk Songs of the Catskills, Chapter 12 - Outlaws and Ruffians, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 57)
    - Folk Songs of the Catskills, Chapter 13 - Scrapes and Escapades, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 58)
    - Folk Songs of the Catskills, Chapter 14 - Merry Ditties, Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 1)
    - Folk Songs of the Catskills, Chapter 15 - Nonsense Songs, Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 2)
    - Folk Songs of the Catskills, Material from Norman Cazden, Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 3)
    - "Folklore Manual", Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 4)
    - "Forgotten Hero of New York's Slave Railway", 1969 (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 5)
    - "George Edwards--Folk Singer of the Catskills", 1955 (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 6)
    - "Harry Siemsen: Teacher of Life", 1956; 1974-1976; Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 7)
    - Haybarn Hill, 1954; Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 8)
    - "Her Name Was Truth", 1950; Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 9)
    - "How We Related Experience and Writing in Early Adolescence", Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 10)
    - "Ideologies and Utopias", 1969 (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 11)
    - Indians, Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 12)
    - "Iree Weaver", Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 13)
    - "Lines Written in the Amphitheater", 1962 (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 14)
    - List of Catskill Residents Interviewed, 1978; Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 15)
    - Little Red School House: Where I Began, Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 16)
    - "Local History: A Neglected Resource", 1942 (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 17)
    - "Local Song Writing in the Catskills", Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 18)
    - "Lookout in the Catskills", Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 19)
    - "The Lower East Side Story: Emphasizing the Mobilization Area", 1962 (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 20)
    - Mr. Bear of the Catskills, Correspondence, 1978 (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 21)
    - Mr. Bear of the Catskills, Early Draft of A Catskill Woodsman: Mike Todd's Story, Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 22-23)
    - Music of the Catskills, Working Title of Folk Songs of the Catskills, Draft Introduction, Correspondence, Chapter Overviews, 1979; Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 24)
    - Music of the Catskills, Working Title of Folk Songs of the Catskills, Draft pages 1-150, Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 25)
    - Music of the Catskills, Working Title of Folk Songs of the Catskills, Draft Pages 151-275, Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 26)
    - Music of the Catskills, Working Title of Folk Songs of the Catskills, Draft Pages 251-303, Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 27)
    - My Book of Short Stories, 1976-1977 (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 28)
    - The New Person, Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 29)
    - Outline for Historical Fiction Stories, 1975 (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 30)
    - "The Place of Folklore in Education", 1953; 1962; Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 31)
    - Poetry, 1969-1970; Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 32)
    - Progressive Education, Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 33)
    - Proposal for a Source Book in American History for Junior High Schools, Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 34)
    - Proposed Book on Catskill People, Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 35)
    - Reflections for a Book and Journal Entry About a Visit to Mt. Sinai Hospital, 1978; Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 36)
    - "A Quest for American Roots", Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 37)
    - "Resource Booklet for the Local Community: Laboratory for Social Learning" by Joan S. Levine with Norman M. Levine and Norman Studer, 1975 (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 38)
    - Reviews by Norman Studer, 1951; Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 39)
    - "Revolt in the American Colleges," by Norman Studer, 1926 (Oversized 1, Folder 10)
    - The Shawangunks, 1968; Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 40)
    - "A Shrine to Freedom Hidden Away in Queens ", Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 41)
    - Sojourner Truth Article Correspondence, 1977 (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 42)
    - "Sojourner Truth Returns to Ulster County", Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 43)
    - Song Making in the Catskills, Notes on Songs, Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 44)
    - Song Making in the Catskills, Notes on Songs, Norma Cazden, 1972; Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 45)
    - "Sons of Liberty in NYC", 1951; Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 46)
    - Speech on Folk Music Possibly Delivered at an Upstate Downstate Concert, Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 47)
    - "The Story of Mike Todd," Mary Bogardus and Norman Studer, 1970; Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 48)
    - Tales from Dry Book, 1963; 1967; 1970; /Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 49)
    - "Three Witch Stories from the Catskills", Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 50)
    - Thoughts on Van Wyck Brothers New England Renaissance, Journal, Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 51)
    - "To Save the Woodland Idea", 1961; Undated (Box 2 (8-Writings), Folder 52)
    - "The Town They Called Peace", 1950; Undated (Box 3 (8-Writings), Folder 1)
    - "Turning Back the Waters of the Ashokan", Undated (Box 3 (8-Writings), Folder 2)
    - UNICEF, In Memory of Steven Rinaldi, Undated (Box 3 (8-Writings), Folder 3)
    - Untitled Manuscript, Folklore and Education, Undated (Box 3 (8-Writings), Folder 4)
    - Untitled Manuscript, Visitors to Downtown Community School, 1970; Undated (Box 3 (8-Writings), Folder 5)
    - Untitled Manuscript, White and Black Folklore, Undated (Box 3 (8-Writings), Folder 6)
    - "The Value of Landmarks in Writing", Undated (Box 3 (8-Writings), Folder 7)
    - "Wartime Education for Democracy at Camp", ca. 1942; 1943 (Box 3 (8-Writings), Folder 8)
    - "'Whirling' and Applejack in the Catskills", 1952 (Box 3 (8-Writings), Folder 9)
    - "The Winter Soldier", 1975 (Box 3 (8-Writings), Folder 10)
    - Woodland Story, Chapter 1 - Beginnings at the Little Red Schoolhouse, Undated (Box 3 (8-Writings), Folder 11-12)
    - Woodland Story, Chapter 2 - Look We Have Made a World, Undated (Box 3 (8-Writings), Folder 13)
    - Woodland Story, Chapter 3 - Reading the Catskill Landscape, Undated (Box 3 (8-Writings), Folder 14)
    - Woodland Story, Chapter 4 - A Fable of Two Communities, Undated (Box 3 (8-Writings), Folder 15)
    - Woodland Story, Chapter 5 - The Reservoir Near Sholam, Undated (Box 3 (8-Writings), Folder 16)
    - Woodland Story, Chapter 6 - George Edwards and Marvin Yale, Undated (Box 3 (8-Writings), Folder 17)
    - Woodland Story, Chapter 7 - Red Hill County, Undated (Box 3 (8-Writings), Folder 18)
    - Woodland Story, Chapter 8 - Our Neighbors and Their Music, Undated (Box 4 (8-Writings), Folder 1)
    - Woodland Story, Chapter 9 - Folklore from a Valley that Died, Undated (Box 4 (8-Writings), Folder 2)
    - Woodland Story, Chapter 10 - Whirling and Songmaking in the Western Catskills, Undated (Box 4 (8-Writings), Folder 3)
    - Woodland Story, Chapter 11 - Mike Todd's Story, Undated (Box 4 (8-Writings), Folder 4)
    - Woodland Story, Chapter 14 - The Last Years, Undated (Box 4 (8-Writings), Folder 5)
    - Woodland Story, Chapter 15 - Mike Todd, Bear Hunter, Undated (Box 4 (8-Writings), Folder 6)
    - Woodland Story, Chapter 16 - Yarns of a Catskill Woodsman, ca. 1955; 1958; Undated (Box 4 (8-Writings), Folder 7)
    - Woodland Story, Chapter 17 - Our Catskill Teachers, Undated (Box 4 (8-Writings), Folder 8)
    - Woodland Story, Chapters on Sojourner Truth and the Guns of Cornell, Undated (Box 4 (8-Writings), Folder 9)
    - Woodland Story, Early Drafts, 1949; Undated (Box 4 (8-Writings), Folder 10)
    - Woodland Story, Footnotes, Undated (Box 4 (8-Writings), Folder 11)
    - Woodland Story, Fragments, Undated (Box 4 (8-Writings), Folder 12)
    - Woodland Story, Outline of Chapters, Undated (Box 4 (8-Writings), Folder 13)
  - Diaries and Travelogues, ca. 1931-1978; Undated; 8.2
    The Diaries and Travelogues subseries consists primarily of travelogues documenting several school field trips and family vacations. The diaries document aspects of Studer's personal landscape, and were kept sporadically.
    - Diary, Long Island, ca. 1931 (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 1)
    - Diary, 1932 (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 2)
    - Gaspe Diary, ca. 1935 (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 3)
    - Gaspe Sketches and Writings, ca. 1935; Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 4)
    - Diary, Transient Camp, ca. 1935; Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 5)
    - Diary, Mt. Sinai Hospital, 1937 (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 6)
    - Trip to East Branch Valley, 1949 (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 7)
    - Diary of Trip to South, ca. 1957 (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 8)
    - European Diary, 1963 (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 9)
    - Western Diary I, 1964 (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 10)
    - Western Diary II, 1965 (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 11)
    - Western Trip, 1965 (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 12)
    - Canadian Trip I, 1966 (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 13)
    - Canadian Trip II, 1966 (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 14)
    - Summer, 1967 (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 15)
    - Scandinavia, 1969 (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 16)
    - Vermont and New Hampshire, ca. 1970 (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 17)
    - Appointment Book and Diary, 1970-1972 (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 18)
    - Diary, 1973 (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 19)
    - Appointment Book, 1974 (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 20)
    - Diary Pages and Appointment Book, 1975 (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 21)
    - Appointment Book, 1976 (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 22)
    - Diary, 1977; ca. 1978 (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 23)
    - Diary, 1978 (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 24)
    - Diaries, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 25)
    - Fragments of a Southern Trip, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 26)
    - LRSH [Little Red School House] Days Diary, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 27)
    - Looking at America, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 28)
    - Part of Diary of Trip to the Southwest, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 29)
    - Taos, Mesa Verde, Yellowstone, Undated (Box 1 (8-Writings), Folder 30)
- Subject Files, 1817-1999; Undated; 9; 3.62 cubic ft.
  The Subject Files series is an accumulation of material representing Studer's two primary interests: folklore and progressive education. Materials include notes, reprints, typescripts, news clippings, bound newspapers, journals, and writings of others. Of particular interest is a master's thesis by Marilyn Kimball entitled George Edwards: Catskill Folksinger. There is a typescript copy of "Merry Ditties: A Collection of Delectable Songs" from various traditional sources and a reprint of "Catskill Lockup Songs," both by Norman Cazden. Also located in this series is a copy of Herbert Haufrecht's "Woodland Serenade." There are three bound volumes of The New Student, a student run newspaper published and printed out of New York City during the 1920s and edited by Studer prior to his entering Columbia University.
  - The Abelardian, 1967 (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - "Abe Sammons' AppleJack", Undated (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - African American History and Folklore, 1972; 1976; Undated (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - "Aggressive Humor on the East Branch," by Herbert Halpert, 1946 (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Alienation, Undated (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - "Along the Kansas Line", Undated (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - American Culture, Undated (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - The American Experience, Englewood Public Schools, ca. 1978 (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - The American Soldier, 1969; Undated (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Animal Woodcuts by Jonathan Fisher, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 11)
  - Anti-Rent War, 1942; 1945; 1960; 1962; Undated (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - "Another Kind of Crockett," by Norman Strong, Undated (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - The Archive of Folk Songs in the Library of Congress, 1974 (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Art Coss, 1944; Undated (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Articles on Folklore in Education and Children's Folklore, 1953; Undated (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Bear Stories, 1946; 1950; 1952; 1959-1960; Undated (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - The Black Panther, 1970 (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Bob Gregory, Undated (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Bowne House, Flushing, New York, Undated (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Brant, Joseph, 1953; Undated (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Canal Transportation, 1961; Undated (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Card with Harriet Tubman, Undated (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Carl Carmer Center for Catskill Mountain and Hudson River Studies, including Studer Exhibit, 1979-1980 (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - The Catskill Canister, 1979-1980 (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Catskill Folk Festival, 1977 (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Catskill Folk Festival, 1978 (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Catskill Folksay, 1947; 1950; Undated (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Catskill Geology, 1957; Undated (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - "Catskill Lockup Songs," by Norman Cazden, 1960 (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Catskill Mountain News, 1948-1958; 1963; Undated (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 29-30)
  - Catskill Mountain Players, 1976-1977 (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - "The Catskill Mountain, A Catskill Folk Song Sampler", 1975 (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Catskill Valley Historical Society, Undated (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Catskills, 1974-1975; Undated (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Center for Educational Interaction, 1975-1976; Undated (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - The Chronicle of Early American Industries, 1949-1955 (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - The Chronicle of Early American Industries, 1956-1962 (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - City Architecture and Preservation, Undated (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Collected Catskill Folklore, 1950; Undated (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Collecting Folklore, 1945; 1952; 1968; Undated (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Community, The Soil for Roots, Undated (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Connecticut History, Undated (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Conservation, Undated (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - Cornwallville Conservation and Gilboa-Leeds Transmission Line Route, 1971; 1973 (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - Country Life, Undated (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 45)
  - Covered Bridges, 1948; 1953; 1955; Undated (Box 1 (9-Subject Files), Folder 46)